(MAN SPEAKING
IN DISTINCTLY ON PA)
PROFESSOR X: The future.
A dark, desolate world.
(IN DISTINCT CHATTER
OVER PA CONTIN U ES)
PROFESSOR X: A world of
war, suffering, loss...
on both sides.
(WOMAN SOBBING)
Mutants and the humans
who dared to help them.
(SOBBING CONTIN U ES)
Fighting an enemy
we cannot defeat.
(MAN SPEAKING
IN DISTINCTLY OVER PA)
(PANTING)
PROFESSOR X: Are we
destined down this path?
Destined to destroy ourselves
like so many species before us?
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Or can we evolve fast
enough to change ourselves?
Change our fate?
(DISTANT GROWLING)
Is the future truly set?
(MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(WH IRRING)
(MU FFLED TH UMPING)
They're here!
(PANTING)
Time's up.
WARPATH: Sentinels!
Sunspot!
KITTY: Let's go.
(PANTING)
(MACH IN ERY WH IRRING)
(GRU NTING)
(GROWLING)
(YELLING)
(GROANS)
(GRU NTING)
(PANTING)
WARPATH: Run!
(GRU NTING)
BLIN K: Go!
(WH ISTLING)
(YELLING)
(GRU NTING)
(GROAN ING)
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRU NTING)
(CHOKING)
(BOTH PANTING)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
(GRU NTS)
(GROANS)
(CHOKING)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
(GRU NTS)
(SCREAMS)
Blink! No!
(MOANS)
(PANTING)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
(ROARING)
(YELLS)
(GROWLS)
(ROARING)
Too late, assholes.
(MAN SOBBING)
Don't move,
you mutant scum!
(WOMAN SCREAMING)
No!
Flat on the ground,
hands behind your head!
(MAN SCREAMING)
(WOMAN SOBBING)
PROFESSOR X:
So few of us left.
KITTY: Professor?
I've found them.
(POWERING U P)
(LIGHTER CLICKS)
BOBBY: Professor!
Bobby.
Hey, Storm.
Hey, kid.
KITTY: Professor,
you made it.
Whenever the Sentinels attack,
Warpath spots them...
then I send Bishop
back to warn us
of the attack
before it happens.
Blink scouts
the next site...
and then we leave before
they ever know we were there.
Because...
we never were.
What do you mean
you were never there?
She projects
Bishop back in time
a few days to
warn the others...
of the coming attack.
So she sends
Bishop back in time?
No, just his consciousness,
into his younger self.
His younger body.
Wow.
This might just work,
Charles.
What might work?
The Sentinel program
was originally
conceived by
Doctor Bolivar Trask.
In the early '70s, he was one of the
world's leading weapons designers.
But, covertly, he had begun
experimenting on mutants...
using their gifts
to fuel his own research.
TRASK: This is extraordinary.
PROFESSOR X: There was one mutant
who had discovered what he was doing.
A mutant with the ability to
transform herself into anyone.
Mystique.
PROFESSOR X:
I knew her as Raven.
We met when
we were children,
grew up together.
She was like
a sister to me.
I tried to help her...
but only succeeded
in driving her away.
She hunted Trask
across the world.
And at the Paris
Peace Accords in 1973,
after the Vietnam War...
she found Trask...
and killed him.
(GU NSHOT)
It was the first
time she killed.
It wasn't her last.
But killing Trask did not
have the outcome she expected.
It only persuaded
the government
of the need
for his program.
(GASPS) PROFESSOR X: They
captured her that day...
tortured her,
experimented on her.
In her DNA,
they discovered the secrets
to her powers of
transformation.
It gave them
the key they needed...
to create weapons that could
adapt to any mutant power.
And in less than 50 years...
the machines that
have destroyed...
so many of our kind
were created. (LOW GROWL)
But it all started
that day in 1973...
the day she first killed.
The day she truly became...
Mystique.
You want to
go back there.
If I can get to her,
stop the assassination...
keep her out
of their hands...
then we can stop the
Sentinels from ever being born.
And end this war
before it ever begins.
Uh, I can send someone
back a couple weeks.
Maybe a month.
But you're talking about
going back decades.
You have the most powerful
brain in the world, Professor...
but the mind can only stretch
so far before it snaps.
It would rip you apart.
I'm sorry.
No one could
survive that trip.
What if someone's mind
has a way of snapping back?
What if someone can heal as
fast as they're ripped apart?
STORM: Okay, spread out.
BISHOP: Take your positions.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH ING)
So I wake up in my younger
body, God knows where.
Then what?
You'll need to go to
my house and find me.
Convince me
of all of this.
Won't you be able
to just read my mind?
I didn't have my
powers in 1973.
Logan, you're going
to have to do for me
what I once did for you.
Lead me, guide me.
I was a very
different man then.
You'll have to be patient
with me. (LOGAN SCOFFS)
Patience is
my strongest suit.
You'll need me as well.
What?
After Mystique left Charles,
she came with me...
and I set her on
a dangerous path.
A darker path.
It's going to take the
two of us, side by side...
at a time when we couldn't
be further apart.
Great.
So where do I find you?
Well, it's complicated.
Basically, your body
will go to sleep
while your mind
travels back in time.
As long as
you're back there,
past and present will
continue to coexist.
But once you wake up...
whatever you've done will
take hold and become history.
And for the rest of us, it will
be the only history that we know.
It will be like the last
50 years never happened.
And this world,
and this war...
the only person who will
remember it is you.
All right, Logan...
I need you to
clear your head
and to stay as
calm as possible.
What? What do you mean?
If your mind gets rocky, it will
be harder for me to hold you...
and you could start to slip
between past and future.
What if I need to
get a little rocky?
Think peaceful thoughts?
Peaceful thoughts...
Do you have any good news?
Well, you don't really age,
so you'll pretty
much look the same.
BOBBY: You won't have
much time in the past.
The Sentinels
will find us.
They always do.
And this time,
we won't be able to run.
We'll have no escape.
This is our last chance.
You really think
this will work?
I have faith in him.
MAGN ETO: It's not him I'm
worried about, it's us.
We were young...
we didn't know
any better.
We will now.
See you all soon.
This might sting a little.
(SCREAMING)
(SOFT '70s SONG PLAYING)
The first time
Ever I saw your face
(WATERBED SLOSH ING)
Whoa.
I thought the sun
Rose in your eyes
(GRU NTS)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
And the moon
and the stars
Were the gifts you gave
LOGAN: Holy shit.
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
It worked.
Hey, what's going on?
Gwen, get dressed.
LOGAN: Who the hell are you?
Hey, I don't know
what's going on.
You're supposed to be
guarding the boss's daughter,
not screwing her.
Well, I didn't
sleep with her.
MAN: No?
No.
I mean, yes, I slept
with her many times.
Jimmy!
That wasn't me.
That was the old me.
I just got here
20 seconds ago.
MAN: Really?
Then what happened
to your clothes?
My... Oh.
Would you believe
me if I told you
I was sent here
from the future?
Huh?
(CH UCKLES)
Get out of here, sweetheart. Yeah.
We're gonna take care of this
comedian. LOGAN: No, you're not.
You're gonna give me the keys to
your car and some money for gas...
or you're gonna wake
up in the hospital.
Trust me, I know how
these things play out.
Oh. Because you're
from the future?
No.
Because of these.
MAN: What the hell?
(GRU NTING)
(GU NSHOTS)
(GROANS)
God damn it!
(GRU NTS)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
(BU LLETS CLATTERING)
(GRU NTING)
(GU NSHOT)
(YELLS)
(GRU NTING)
Peaceful thoughts.
(PEOPLE SPEAKING IN DISTINCTLY)
SENATOR BRICKMAN: We are reviewing
all of our defense expenditures...
and all the black books
are being opened.
We can't support a weapon
that targets our own citizens.
If these mutants,
as you describe...
are already
living among us...
then they are living
here peacefully.
PARKER: We haven't had an
incident in over 10 years.
After what happened
in Cuba?
PARKER: That was
never confirmed.
We have very real
enemies out there...
the Russians, the Chinese.
We are talking about
a tenth of a tenth...
of a tenth
of our population.
Allow me to read
something to you.
Please.
This was acquired by
our friends at the CIA.
It's a dissertation...
written by a mutant
at Oxford University.
And I quote...
"To Homo Neanderthalensis...
"his mutant cousin,
Homo Sapiens... "
which is us...
"was an aberration.
"The arrival of the mutated
human species, Homo Sapiens...
"was followed by the immediate
extinction of their less evolved kin. "
Well...
Now, we are
the Neanderthal.
Speak for yourself,
Dr. Trask.
(ALL LAUGH ING)
(CH UCKLES)
You know, when you sent
our soldiers to Vietnam...
without the weapons they
needed to win the war...
you underestimated
your enemy.
(CH UCKLING) You do that
with this enemy...
Mmm...
and it won't be some border
skirmish halfway around the world.
This time, the war will
be for our streets...
our cities, our homes...
and by the time you see
the need for my program...
it will be too late...
and you will have lost
two wars in one lifetime.
We are sorry,
Dr. Trask...
but your
Sentinel Program...
it ain't gonna fly.
(H ELICOPTER BLADES WH IRRING)
Can I help you, Colonel?
Just here to give our
boys a proper send-off.
I'm sorry, sir, but we have
orders. This is a quarantined area.
Stand aside, soldier.
That's an order.
SOLDIER: Atten-hut!
At ease.
(CLEARS TH ROAT)
What is all this?
Lab reports,
blood tests.
It's all getting packed up
and shipped back.
Where is it going?
Same place they are.
Trask Industries.
STRYKER:
Let's go, gentlemen.
I'm taking you out
of this shit show.
HAVOK: Shipping home?
Not just yet.
What are you doing
with those?
Something to make the ride
a little smoother.
I'm transferring you
to a private facility...
where we can run
a few more tests.
(COLON EL SAN DERS
CLEARS TH ROAT)
Your men
are not military.
Private outfit.
We're authorized
to remand these men.
Hmm.
These troops
are going home.
Well, Colonel, I don't believe you
have jurisdiction in this matter.
I'm afraid I do, son.
I'm sorry, who are you?
The question is,
Major...
...who are you?
(GRU NTS)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(GRU NTS)
(CHOKING)
Raven!
That's not my name.
(GRU NTING)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
I had that.
I know.
Let's move out.
Come on, let's go.
HAVOK: Where's Erik?
I'm on my own now.
Let's go! Move it!
(SOLDIERS
YELLING IN DISTINCTLY)
Hold that plane!
Wouldn't wanna leave these boys
in this godforsaken country.
SOLDIER: Yes, sir.
You're not coming
with us, are you?
My war's not over.
The enemy is
still out there.
The four privates,
where did they go?
They were headed
towards the tarmac.
Can I help you?
Uh... Yeah, what happened to the school?
The school's been shut for
years. Are you a parent?
(SCOFFS) I sure as hell
hope not. Who are you?
I'm Hank. Hank McCoy.
I look after the house now.
You're Beast?
Look at you. I guess
you're a late bloomer.
I don't know what
you're talking about,
but I'm gonna have
to ask you to leave.
(GRU NTS)
So where's the Professor?
There's no professor here.
You're pretty strong
for a scrawny kid.
You sure there's not
a little Beast in there?
No, he's not here.
Come on, Beast.
Come on, Beastie.
No.
(GRU NTS) Hey!
I said
the school's closed.
You need to leave. Not
until I see the Professor.
There's no professor here,
I told you that.
Look, kid. You and I are
gonna be good friends.
(GRU NTS)
(GROANS)
You just don't know it yet.
Professor!
(GROANS)
(GRU NTS)
Professor!
(ROARS)
(GRU NTS)
(HAN K ROARS)
(LOGAN SCREAMING)
(ROARS)
CHARLES: Hank?
What's going on here?
Professor?
Please don't
call me that.
Why?
You know this guy?
Yeah, he looks
slightly familiar.
Get off the bloody
chandelier, Hank.
(GLASS CLIN KING)
You can walk.
You're a perceptive one.
I thought Erik...
Which makes it
slightly perplexing that
you missed our
sign on the way in.
This is private property,
my friend.
I'm gonna have to ask him
to ask you to leave.
Well. (SIGHS)
I'm afraid
I can't do that...
because I was
sent here for you.
Well, tell whoever it was
that sent you that I'm busy.
That's gonna be
a little tricky...
because the person
who sent me was you.
What?
About 50 years from now.
Like in the future,
50 years from now?
Yeah.
I sent you from the future?
CHARLES: Piss off.
If you had your powers, you'd
know I was telling the truth.
How do you know
I don't have my p...
Who are you?
LOGAN: I told you.
Are you CIA?
No.
You've been watching me?
I know you, Charles.
We've been friends
for years.
I know your powers
came when you were 9.
I know you thought you were
going crazy when it started...
all the voices
in your head.
And it wasn't
until you were 12...
that you realized all the voices
were in everyone else's head.
Do you want me to go on?
I never told anyone that.
Not yet, no,
but, you will.
All right,
you've piqued my interest.
What do you want?
We have to stop Raven.
I need your help.
We need your help.
I think I'd like
to wake up now.
(SIGHS)
What does she
have to do with this?
CHARLES: So you're saying...
they took Raven's
power, and what?
They weaponized it?
Yep.
She is unique.
Yeah, she is, Hank.
LOGAN: In the beginning, the
Sentinels were just targeting mutants.
Then they began to identify
the genetics in non-mutants...
who would eventually have mutant
children and grandchildren.
Many of the humans tried to
help us, but it was a slaughter.
leaving only the worst
of humanity in charge.
I've been in a lot of wars.
I'd never seen
anything like this.
And it all starts
with her.
Let's just say
for the sake of...
the sake, that I
choose to believe you...
that I choose to help you.
Raven won't listen to me.
(SIGHS)
Her heart and soul
belong to someone else now.
LOGAN: I know.
That's why we're
gonna need Magneto, too.
HAN K: Erik?
(LAUGH ING)
You do know where he is?
Yeah.
(LAUGH ING)
He's where he belongs.
You're just
gonna walk out?
Ooh, top marks. Like I
said, you are perceptive.
The Professor I know would
never turn his back...
on someone who'd
lost their path.
Especially
someone he loved.
You know...
I think I do
remember you now.
Yeah. We came to
you a long time ago...
seeking your help.
And I'm gonna say to you
what you said to us then.
Fuck off.
Listen to me,
you little shit.
I've come a long way, and I've
watched a lot of people die.
Good people. Friends.
If you're gonna
wallow in self-pity...
and do nothing, then you're
gonna watch the same thing...
you understand?
We all have to
die sometime.
Told you there was
no professor here.
What the hell
happened to him?
HANK: He lost everything.
Erik, Raven...
his legs.
(SIGHS) We built the school,
the labs, this whole place...
then, just after
the first semester...
the war in Vietnam
got worse.
Many of the teachers...
and older students
were drafted.
It broke him.
He retreated into himself.
I wanted to help,
do something...
so I designed a serum
to treat his spine...
derived from the same formula
that helps me control my mutation.
(SIGHS) I take just enough
to keep myself balanced...
but he takes too much.
I tried easing him back...
but he just couldn't bear
the pain, the voices.
The treatment
gives him his legs...
but it's not enough.
He's...
He's just lost too much.
(SIGHS)
YOU NG RAVEN: You're
not scared of me?
YOU NG CHARLES: I always believed I
couldn't be the only one in the world.
Charles Xavier.
Raven.
You're hungry and alone.
Take whatever you want.
We've got lots of food.
You don't have to steal.
In fact...
you never have to
steal again.
And that's a promise.
CHARLES: I'll
help you get her.
Not for any of your
future shite, but for her.
Fair enough.
But I'll tell you this.
You don't know Erik.
That man is a monster.
A murderer.
You think you can
convince Raven to change?
To come home?
That's splendid.
But what makes you think
you can change him?
Because you and Erik sent
me back here together.
HAN K: The room
they're holding him in
was built during
the Second World War...
when there was
a shortage of steel.
So the foundation is pure
concrete and sand. No metal.
CHARLES:
He's being held...
a hundred floors
beneath the most
heavily guarded
building on the planet.
LOGAN: Why is he in there?
What, he forgot
to mention?
(SN ICKERING)
Uh, J FK.
He killed...
(CH UCKLING)
What else explains a bullet
miraculously curving through the air?
Erik's always had
a way with guns.
Are you sure you want
to carry on with this?
This is your plan,
not mine.
HAN K: We don't have any
resources to get us in.
CHARLES: Or out.
It's just me and Hank.
I knew a guy.
Yeah, he'd be
a young man now.
Grew up outside of D.C.
(CH UCKLING)
He could get
into anywhere.
I just don't know how the hell
we're gonna find him.
Is Cerebro out
of the question?
We have a phonebook.
I thought you'd be getting
ready for your trip, sir.
I just came to
grab a couple files.
Is that a new scarf?
It's nice.
Thank you.
(BEEPS)
(BREATH TREMBLING)
(GASPS)
Dr. Trask?
One second.
Oh.
We added some names
to the Paris meeting.
Thank you.
Is something wrong, sir?
No. It's nothing.
Would you mind
typing up my itinerary?
I don't wanna
miss anything.
LOGAN: Here, here, here.
CHARLES: Where?
Just stop here.
All right, all right.
Next time I'm driving.
Don't get used to it.
(CAR DOOR CLOSES)
(MAN TALKING ON TV)
(SIGHS)
What's he done now?
I will just write you a
check for whatever he took.
We just need
to talk to him.
Peter! The cops
are here. Again.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(PLAYING PING-PONG)
PETER: What do
you guys want?
I didn't do anything.
I've been here all day.
Just relax, Peter.
We're not cops.
Of course you're not.
If you were,
you wouldn't be
driving a rental car.
How did you know
we've got a rental car?
I checked your registration when
you were walking to the door.
I also had
some time to kill
so I went through
your rental agreement.
Saw you were from out
of town. Are you FBl?
No, you're not cops. Hey, what's
with this gifted youngsters place?
That's an old card.
He's fascinating.
He's a pain in the arse.
What, a teleporter?
No, he's just fast.
And when I knew him
he wasn't so... young.
PETER: Young?
You're just old.
So you're not afraid
to show your powers?
What powers? What
are you talking about?
Do you see
something strange here?
Nothing anybody would
believe if you told them.
(ARCADE GAME PINGING)
So, who are you?
What do you want?
LOGAN: We need your
help, Peter. For what?
To break into a highly
secured facility...
and to get someone out.
Prison break?
That's illegal, you know.
Um...
Well, only if
you get caught.
So, what's in it for me?
You, you kleptomaniac, get
to break into the Pentagon.
How do I know
I can trust you?
Because we're
just like you.
Show him.
(BREATH ES DEEPLY)
That's cool,
but it's disgusting.
TOU R GU IDE: Built in 1943, the Pentagon
is the world's largest office building...
housing more than
25,000 military employees...
stretched over six
million square feet.
Where's the bathroom?
GIRL: He always needs
to pee! (ALL LAUGH)
(STATIC CRACKLES)
(DOOR BUZZING)
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Yeah, we're getting broadcast
signal down here. What's going on?
Damn it, call Maintenance,
get them down here.
(CH UCKLES)
(SHOES SQU EAKING)
(VIBRATING)
(RUMBLING)
(ALARM BLARING)
...fought for and captured the island
of Iwo Jima from the Japanese Empire.
Now, this month-long battle...
included some of
the fiercest fighting
during World War
ll in the Pacific...
(CH EF SPEAKING FRENCH)
(ALARM BLARING)
(GRU NTS)
ERIK: In three seconds, those
doors are going to open...
and 20 guards will
be here to shoot us.
I know. That's what
I'm waiting for.
What are you doing?
I'm holding your neck so
you don't get whiplash.
What?
(SLOWLY) Whiplash.
GUARD: Don't move!
(GRU NTS)
(ALL GROAN)
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
PETER: You're
good, it'll pass.
It happens with everyone.
You must have done
something pretty serious.
What did you do, man?
What did you do?
What did you do? Why'd
they have you in there?
For killing the President.
Ah. Wow.
(WH ISPERS) Shit.
The only thing
I'm guilty of
is fighting for
people like us.
You take karate?
You know karate, man?
I don't know karate.
But I know crazy.
(CH UCKLES)
Ladies and gentlemen, boys and
girls, this is a Code Red situation.
We are evacuating
the entire floor...
so that my associate and I...
can, uh, secure the prison.
Who are you?
We're special operations,
CB...
FB-CID.
Perhaps you didn't hear me
when first I spoke...
but it is imperative
that you understand...
we're in a complete
lockdown situation.
We have to get you
to the third floor...
(GRU NTS)
Oh, I'm sorry.
Were you finished?
(GRU NTING)
They told me
you control metal.
"They"?
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
You know, my mom once knew
a guy who could do that.
I'm sorry, I'm just not
very good with violence.
(ELEVATOR BELL DINGS)
Charles?
(GRU NTS)
(CHARLES GROANS)
Good to see you too,
old friend.
And walking.
No thanks to you.
You're the last person in the
world I expected to see today.
Believe me...
I wouldn't be here
if I didn't have to.
If we get you out of here,
we do it my way.
No killing.
No helmet.
I couldn't disobey
you even if I wanted.
I'm never getting
inside of that head again.
I need your word, Erik.
Nobody move!
Hold it right there!
Charles.
GUARD: Don't move.
Hands up,
or we will shoot!
Freeze them, Charles.
I can't.
Hands up!
(CLATTERING)
No!
(MELLOW '70s SONG PLAYING)
If I could save time
in a bottle
The first thing
that I'd like to do
Is to save every day
Till eternity passes away
Just to spend them with you
If I could make days
last forever
If words could make
wishes come true
I'd save every day
Like a treasure and then
Again,
I would spend them with you
But there never seems
to be enough time
To do the things
you want to do
Once you find them
I've looked around
enough to know
That you're the one I want
to go through time with
(ALL GRU NTING)
(ALARM CONTIN U ES RINGING)
Thanks, kid.
CHARLES: Peter,
thank you very, very much.
You take care.
PETER: Hey, I saw your
flight plan in the cockpit.
Why are you going to Paris?
Imagine if they were metal.
CHARLES: Do me a favor
and return it for me. Okay.
And, Peter?
Take it slow.
(CH UCKLES)
Where did they
dig you up?
You're gonna find
this hard to believe...
but, uh, you sent me.
You and Charles.
From the future.
(SIGHS)
How did you lose them?
The treatment for my
spine affects my DNA.
You sacrificed your powers
so you could walk?
I sacrificed my powers
so that I could sleep.
What do you know about it?
I've lost my fair share.
Ha.
Dry your eyes, Erik.
It doesn't justify
what you've done.
You have no idea
what I've done.
I know that you took the
things that mean the most to me.
Well, maybe you should have
fought harder for them.
If you want a fight,
Erik...
LOGAN: Sit down.
... I will give you a fight!
Let him come.
You abandoned me!
You took her away...
and you abandoned me!
Angel.
Azazel.
Emma.
Banshee.
Mutant brothers
and sisters...
all dead!
(GRU NTS)
Countless others...
experimented on.
Butchered!
Erik!
Where were you, Charles?
We were supposed
to protect them!
Where were you when your
own people needed you?
Hiding! You and Hank!
Pretending to be
something you're not!
Erik!
You abandoned us all.
(SIGH ING)
(PANTING)
So, you were
always an asshole.
(SCOFFS)
I take it we're best
buddies in the future.
(CH UCKLES)
I spent a lot of years
trying to bring
you down, bub.
How does that
work out for you?
You're like me.
You're a survivor.
Do you wanna pick
all that shit up?
(FRENCH DISCO MUSIC PLAYING)
(ALL LAUGH ING)
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(LAUGHS)
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
General, maybe you should slow down,
we have a big day tomorrow.
We're celebrating, captain. It's not every day you win
a war, let alone against the American devils.
I'm getting another bottle.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Excuse me.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
I'm pretty sure it was my fault.
You speak Vietnamese.
I'm an interpreter.
I speak many tongues.
Let me buy you another drink...
unless you're here with someone.
I'm alone.
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
A bottle of Johnnie Walker please.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
You're going to the Summit tomorrow?
A pretty girl interested in politics...
Looks can be deceiving.
Lady.
Show me more, baby?
Clothes off?
What's the matter, baby? You don't
think I look pretty like this?
(GRU NTS)
(GLASS SHATTERS)
(CHOKING)
(GASPING)
(SQU EAKING)
(SNORING)
Fancy a game?
It's been a while.
I'm not in the mood
for games, thank you.
ERIK: I haven't had
a real sip in ten years.
(SIGHS)
(SWALLOWS)
I didn't kill
the President.
The bullet curved, Erik.
Because I was
trying to save him.
They took me out
before I could.
Why would you
try and save him?
Because he was one of us.
(SCOFFS)
You must think me
so foolish.
We've always said they
would come after us.
I never imagined they'd
use Raven's DNA to do it.
When did you last see her?
(CLICKS TONGU E)
The day I left for Dallas.
And how was she?
Strong.
Driven.
Loyal.
How... How was she?
She was...
We were...
I could see why she
meant so much to you.
You should be proud
of her, Charles.
She's out there
fighting for our cause.
Your cause.
The girl I raised was
not capable of killing.
You didn't raise her,
you grew up with her.
She couldn't stay a little girl
forever, that's why she left.
She left because you
got inside her head.
That's not my power.
She made a choice.
But now we know where
that choice leads, don't we?
She's going to
murder Trask,
they're going
to capture her...
and then they're
going to wipe us out.
Not if we get
to her first.
Not if we change
history tomorrow.
I'm sorry, Charles...
for what happened.
I truly am.
It's been a while since
I've played. (CLEARS TH ROAT)
I'll go easy on you.
Might finally
be a fair fight.
You have the first move.
The diplomats from
all around the world
are arriving here
today at the Hotel Royal.
It's an historic day.
It's the, uh,
official ending
of the United States' military
involvement in Vietnam.
There we have the South
Vietnamese Foreign Minister...
with other South
Vietnamese dignitaries.
The Summit doesn't begin
for another hour.
The hotel has arranged
a private room
upstairs for
your special guests.
TRASK: That will be
plenty of time.
(IN DISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Good afternoon, everyone.
Hello, thank you for coming.
Congratulations on
winning this war.
Now, I know you all
have hands to shake
and photos to
take downstairs...
so I will get
right to the point.
There is a new
enemy out there.
An enemy that will render
your arsenals useless...
your armies powerless...
and your nations
defenseless.
TRASK: You will need a new weapon
for this war. I call them Sentinels.
Named after
the ancient guardians
that stood at
the gates of the citadel.
(GRU NTS)
They have the aeronautic
capabilities of a Harrier jet.
Armed with guns
that can fire off...
more than 2,000 rounds per minute
of thermoceramic ammunition.
But size, power,
speed...
you could find that
at Lockheed or Boeing.
No, what makes the
Sentinels so special...
is the ability to target
the mutant X-gene.
A genetic
guidance system
that can lock onto a mark a half a
mile away. (SPEAKING IN DISTINCTLY)
It won't trigger unless it
has identified the target.
With this weapon,
there will be
no human
collateral damage.
If I turn it on, the system
couldn't even activate in here.
(BEEPING)
Unless there's a mutant.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
There has to be
some kind of mistake.
My machines
don't make mistakes.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
What are you?
(MAN SPEAKS VIETNAMESE)
I assure you...
TRASK: No, don't shoot it.
I assure you,
I don't know what
you're talking about.
(SPEAKING VIETNAMESE)
(GRU NTING)
ERIK: Raven!
(GRU NTS)
Raven? Raven!
(SH U DDERING)
Raven?
(BEEPING)
Charles?
We've come for you,
Erik and I.
Together.
RAVEN: I never thought
I'd see you again.
CHARLES: I made you
a promise a long time ago
that I would protect you.
(GRU NTING)
MAN: Wolverine!
(GASPING)
CHARLES: I'm going
to keep you safe.
I'm going to keep you
out of their hands.
Erik?
What are you doing?
Securing our future.
Forgive me,
Mystique.
As long as you're out
there, we'll never be safe.
Erik...
Use your power,
Charles. Stop him.
He can't.
(CROWD GASPING)
(GROAN ING)
KITTY: He's slipping back.
I'm losing him.
(PANTING)
(GRU NTING)
(CROWD EXCLAIMING)
(ALL GASPING)
LOGAN: Stryker!
STRYKER: Someone will finish
what we've started, Wolverine!
One day!
(GRU NTING)
(SCREAMS)
Restrain him.
(CROWD CLAMORING)
(GROAN ING)
(SCREAMING)
Erik!
Where am I?
Huh?
How the hell
did I get here?
What? You came to us.
Who are you?
Charles.
Charles Xavier!
I don't know you.
Huh?
What the hell is that?
Whoa. Whoa. Look, I can
deal with this. Just go.
Stop Erik!
Erik, please...
I'm sorry.
Erik...
(CROWD SCREAMING)
(GROAN ING)
(GASPS)
You're Logan, that's Hank
McCoy, I'm Charles Xavier.
You spent the last
couple of days with us.
You're on acid.
Somebody gave you
really bad acid, yeah?
(RATTLING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GRU NTS)
Just hold on tight,
we'll get through
this together.
(KITTY GROANS)
Oh, my God, Kitty.
She's wounded
pretty bad.
(GROAN ING)
(CLAMORING)
(ROARING)
(KITTY WH IMPERING)
I got him.
(GASPS)
Professor?
What happened to you?
I just saw someone
who's gonna
bring me a lot
of pain someday.
(POLICE SIRENS WAILING)
Where's Raven?
Gone.
What?
We have to get
out of here.
We want to know if there's
any sort of connection with...
(ALL CLAMORING)
Yesterday,
the Paris Peace Summit...
was rocked by the appearance
of unidentified assailants...
the likes of which
the world has never seen.
Mass hysteria has gripped
the nation as people ask...
"Where did they come from?
Will they be back?"
And most importantly,
"Are they friend or foe?"
That was London
correspondent Toby Elliot...
reporting from the
Paris Peace Summit yesterday.
What the hell are we dealing
with here? Off the record.
Two days ago, this
man, Erik Lehnsherr...
escaped from a maximum security
prison inside the Pentagon.
We believe
that this woman
is a former associate
of Lehnsherr's.
They were together
in Cuba,
the day of
the crisis in '62.
He was also implicated
in Kennedy's assassination.
What about that thing?
MAN: We don't know what
that thing is, sir.
Actually, we really don't
know what any of them are.
Yes. Yes, we do.
They're mutants.
He has the power
to control metal.
Last I checked,
that's what
most of your weapons
were made of.
And she can transform
into anyone.
A general,
a secret serviceman.
Even you,
Mr. President.
She could walk
into this office...
and order a nuclear strike
if she was in the mood.
And that's only
two of them.
Do we have any
countermeasures? Any defense?
I was waiting for you
to ask me that question.
That's an experimental program,
sir. Strictly off the books.
(DOG BARKS)
You're telling me these
mutants are out in the world...
and our best defense
are these giant metal robots?
Many of the mutants
look like us.
My Sentinels can
tell the difference.
I have eight prototypes
ready to go.
They're built out of
a space-age polymer,
not an ounce
of metal on them.
I want to make
a demonstration.
I want the world to know
that we can protect them.
What do you need to get
these things operational?
I already gave that
number to Congress.
Unfortunately, they
elected to shut me down.
It's going to cost a
bit more to turn them on.
N IXON: Whatever you need.
TRASK: Oh,
and one more thing.
If we do manage to capture
them, I would like her.
For research purposes,
of course.
(N EWSREADER SPEAKING FRENCH)
(SPEAKING FRENCH)
Terrible thing.
What is?
Being born like that.
Is it?
Can you imagine...
Looking in the mirror and seeing that
staring back at you?
Yes, I can.
Where do you think she comes from?
You think she has a family?
Yes.
She does.
(N EWSREADER SPEAKING
FRENCH ON TV)
(BEGGING IN FRENCH)
If I see so much
as a screw move,
I will jam this
into your throat.
How did you find me?
You taught me well.
It's been a long time
since we were this close.
I missed you.
You tried to kill me.
So the rest of us
could live.
What do you mean?
We received a message
from the future.
Don't lie to me.
I never have,
and I never will.
Humans use your blood,
your genes,
to create a weapon
that wipes us all out.
I was only doing
what I thought
necessary to secure
our future.
So what's to stop me
from killing you
right now and
securing my future?
Nothing.
It doesn't matter
anymore.
They have your DNA. Your
blood was on the street.
Whose fault was that?
Mine.
I've seen their plans.
They're creating a weapon.
And now they have what they
need to take it further.
We have to strike now, while
we still hold the upper hand.
I've seen too many
friends die, Erik.
I don't want a war.
I only want the man
who murdered them.
This is war.
What happened to you?
Did you lose your way
while I was gone?
Are you still Charles' Raven?
Or are you Mystique?
Trask is the enemy.
Killing one man isn't enough.
It never was for you.
Goodbye, Erik.
(GRU NTING)
LOGAN: What happened?
Come on.
Can he walk?
He needs his treatment.
Hank, I can hear them.
I know. It's okay.
Can you make it stop?
I'll get them.
(GROANS)
LOGAN: Hey, hey.
Pull yourself together.
It's not over yet.
(PANTING)
You don't believe that.
How do you know?
CHARLES: As these go...
this comes back.
They all come back.
Look.
I'm still here...
and she's still out there.
We need your help, Charles.
Not like this.
I need you.
We can't find Raven.
Not without your powers.
(FOOTSTEPS APPROACH ING)
HAN K: I added a little extra
because you missed a dose.
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
Charles.
(IN HALES SHARPLY)
Hank, do me a favor.
Would you help me
to my study, please?
Come on, I got you.
(CHARLES GRU NTS)
Are you sure
about this?
Absolutely not.
TRASK: This creature
is extraordinary.
Her genes could hold the key
to mutation itself.
I need more.
That's all they were able to
scrape off the pavement in Paris.
More than blood.
I need brain tissue...
spinal fluid, bone marrow.
Imagine...
Sentinels that
could transform,
adapt to any target.
If I could just get
my hands on her.
This girl could leap
the program forward years...
decades into the future.
How old is your
son now, Major?
Jason?
He's coming up on ten now,
if you can believe it.
Eight years
from fighting age.
And how many of
our sons and brothers
did we just ship
home in body bags?
Maybe fifty,
fifty-five thousand?
And how many more
on the other side?
Never before...
in all of human history...
has there been a cause which
could unite us as a species.
Until now.
You really hate,
mutants, don't you?
On the contrary,
I rather admire them.
The things they can do.
I see mutants
as our salvation.
A common enemy.
A common struggle
against the ultimate enemy.
Extinction.
I believe
our new friends...
are going to help us
usher in a new era, Bill.
A new era of genuine...
and long-lasting peace.
MAN OVER PA:
Attention, attention.
Transport departure
in two hours.
Repeat. Transport
departure in two hours.
(SIGHS) When was the last
time you were down here?
The last time we went
looking for students.
A lifetime ago.
(ELECTRICAL WH IRRING)
AUTOMATED FEMALE VOICE:
Welcome, Professor.
(SIGH ING)
HAN K: Raven's wounded.
She won't be moving fast.
(BLOWS)
These are muscles I haven't
stretched in a long time.
(GASPS)
(IN DISTINCT SHOUTING)
(WEEPING AN D YELLING)
(IN DISTINCT SHOUTING
CONTIN U ES)
(GROAN ING)
Charles!
(SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
Charles? It's all right.
(PANTING)
I'll go check
the generator.
It's not the
machinery, is it?
I can't do this.
My mind...
Yes, you can.
(STAMMERING) It won't take
it. You're just a little rusty.
You don't understand. It's
not a question of being rusty.
I can flip the switches.
I can turn the knobs.
But my power comes from
here. It comes from...
And it's broken.
I feel like one
of my students.
Helpless.
It was a mistake
coming down here.
freeing Erik.
This whole thing has
been one bloody mistake.
I'm sorry, Logan, but they
sent back the wrong man.
You're right.
I am.
Actually, it was
supposed to be you.
But I was the only one who
could physically make the trip.
And, uh...
And I don't know
how long I've got here.
But I do know that
a long time ago...
actually, a long
time from now...
I was your most
helpless student.
And you unlocked
my mind.
You showed me
what I was.
what I could be.
I don't know how
to do that for you.
You're right.
I don't.
But I know
someone who might.
Hmm.
Look into my mind.
You saw what
I did to Cerebro.
You don't want me
inside your head.
There's no damage
you can do...
that hasn't already
been done. Trust me.
Come on.
(SCREAMING)
Hey.
Hey, Logan.
Hi, Jean.
Kill me.
I love you.
(GROANS)
(SCREAMING)
You poor, poor man.
Look past me.
No, I don't want
your suffering.
I don't want your future!
Look past my future.
Look for your future.
That's it.
(SIGHS)
(IN DISTINCT TALKING)
Charles.
(CH UCKLES)
So this is what
becomes of us.
Erik was right.
Humanity
does this to us.
Not if we show
them a better path.
You still believe?
Just because someone
stumbles, loses their way...
it doesn't mean
they're lost forever.
Sometimes we all need
a little help.
Oh, I'm not
the man I was.
I open my mind...
and it almost
overwhelms me.
You're afraid,
and Cerebro knows it.
All those voices...
so much pain.
It's not their pain
you're afraid of.
It's yours, Charles.
And as frightening
as it may be...
that pain will
make you stronger.
If you allow
yourself to feel it...
embrace it...
it will make you more powerful
than you ever imagined.
It's the greatest
gift we have...
to bear their pain
without breaking.
And it's born...
from the most human power.
Hope.
Please, Charles...
we need you to hope again.
Find what you were
looking for?
HAN K: The power's
back on.
Yes.
Yes, it is.
(TRAIN WH ISTLE BLOWING)
(GRU NTS)
(METAL CLAN KING)
(ELECTRICAL WH IRRING)
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
(WIN D HOWLING)
(MOAN ING)
BOBBY: She's lost
too much blood.
She can't keep
going like this.
We have no choice,
Bobby.
We can wake him up.
No!
They need more time.
I had...
a glimpse into the past.
If we wake Logan now...
we may set our fate
on an even darker course.
They need more time.
(SIGHS)
(KITTY GROAN ING)
(WOMAN AN NOU NCING
IN FRENCH OVER PA)
Raven, stop.
Stop running.
Charles?
Where are you?
Back at the house...
where you should be.
I need you to come home.
I know what
I need to do.
If you kill Trask...
you will be creating
countless more just like him.
Then I'll kill
them, too.
Those are Erik's words,
not yours.
Oh!
The girl I grew up with
wasn't capable of killing.
She was good...
fair, full of compassion.
I have compassion.
Just not for Trask.
He's murdered
too many of us.
Shut her down, Charles.
Get in her head.
CHARLES: She's
not letting me in.
I'm barely holding on.
I'm not strong enough yet.
(IN DISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GASPS)
I know what
Trask has done...
but killing him
will not bring them back.
It will set you
on a path...
from which
there is no return.
An endless cycle
of killing.
Us and them, until
there is nothing left.
But we can stop it,
right now, you and I.
You just have to
come home.
I have to?
You haven't changed
at all, Charles.
Like I said...
I know exactly
what I have to do.
(IN DISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Where is she?
(CH UCKLES) She's in an
airport, boarding a plane.
LOGAN: A plane to where?
CHARLES: Washington, D.C.
Guys, there's something
I need to show you.
We're going
backwards in time.
I set the system
I designed...
to record any news about Paris
over all three networks...
and PBS.
All three? Wow.
Yeah, and PBS.
Look what I found.
Tomorrow, in front
of the White House,
the President will
make his announcement.
He will be joined by
Secretary of Defense Laird...
and has even sought the help of
renowned scientist Bolivar Trask...
his special advisor
to combat this mutant issue.
The White House
has asked...
CHARLES: Raven
doesn't realize...
that if she kills Trask
at an event like that...
with the whole
world watching...
Then I came a long way
for nothing.
HAN K: And there's more bad
news. I saw in a report...
they found traces
of her blood in Paris.
For all we know,
they already have her DNA...
which is all they'd need.
To create the Sentinels
of the future.
There's a theory
in quantum physics...
that time is immutable.
It's like a river. You can
throw a pebble into it...
and create a ripple, but the
current always corrects itself.
No matter what
you do, the river
just keeps flowing
in the same direction.
What are you
trying to say?
What I'm saying is...
what if the war
is inevitable?
What if she's meant
to kill Trask?
What if this is just
simply who she is?
Just because someone
stumbles, loses their way...
doesn't mean
they're lost forever.
(CH UCKLES)
No, I don't believe
that theory, Hank.
And I cannot believe
that is who she is.
Ready the plane.
We're going
to Washington.
You all right?
Getting there.
(SIGHS)
Whatever happens today, I need
you to promise me something.
You've looked into my mind
and seen a lot of bad...
but you've seen
the good, too.
The X-Men.
Promise me
you'll find us.
Use your power,
bring us together.
Guide us. Lead us.
Storm. Scott.
Jean.
Remember those names.
There are so many of us.
We will need you,
Professor.
I'll do my best.
Your best is enough.
Trust me.
(WIN D HOWLING)
There's 12 carriers
inbound, 10 miles!
They've found us.
REPORTER: Thousands of people
will be gathered here today.
They've come from
all over the world...
to witness history,
along with news crews...
from at least 50
different countries.
Thank you.
(BEEPS)
Can I see your
invitations, please?
Yes, you may.
These two are with me.
Go ahead.
Thank you.
CHARLES: Logan!
SECU RITY OFFICER:
Please, this way, sir.
(IN DISTINCT VOICES IN H EAD)
I haven't found her yet.
But she has to be here.
AN NOU NCER: The President
of the United States.
(PATRIOTIC MUSIC PLAYS)
(CROWD CH EERING)
My fellow Americans...
today we face the gravest
threat in our history...
mutants.
(VOICES RESUME)
We have prepared
for this threat.
(IN DISTINCT VOICES IN H EAD)
In the immortal words
of Robert Oppenheimer...
"Behold.
"The world will never be
the same again. "
(PATRIOTIC MUSIC PLAYING)
(CROWD CH EERING)
(COU NTRY MUSIC
PLAYING ON RADIO)
Can I help you?
No, you can't.
(STATIC)
Here they come.
(IN DISTINCT VOICES IN H EAD)
RAVEN: This is for you,
brothers and sisters.
Raven?
I have her.
(WITH RAVEN'S VOICE)
Let me go, Charles.
There. You see?
Secret Serviceman.
Left of the stage.
Got him.
CHARLES: Go.
(SENTIN ELS POWERING U P)
What the hell
are you doing?
I didn't tell you
to activate them.
I didn't.
(CROWD GASPING)
CHARLES: Raven, please, listen to me.
We've been given a second
chance to define who we are.
Don't do this.
Gentlemen, you cannot
pass this point.
We can't stop that many.
No, but we can
slow them down.
(CROWD CH EERING)
(SCREAMING)
Erik!
(SCREAMING CONTIN U ES)
Ah!
(PANTING)
Storm!
(GROANS)
(SNARLS)
(YELLING)
Go, go, go!
(MEN CLAMORING)
MAN: Watch your head!
(SIRENS WAILING)
MAN 1: Go, go, go!
MAN 2: Take us to DEFCON 3.
Mr. President,
we are Code Red.
MAN 3: What's our air
defense readiness?
MAN 2: All our air
defenses are ready one.
N IXON: What the hell
happened out there?
I will fix it.
You said that before.
I wanted to
make a statement.
Now the whole goddamn world
knows we can't protect them.
TRASK: I will fix it.
N IXON:
You damn well better.
(GRU NTS)
(CROWD SCREAMING)
Charles!
No, no, no...
(GRU NTS)
(BOTH PANTING)
(FEMALE DISPATCH ER SPEAKING
OVER RADIO)
(SIRENS WAILING)
(BOTH PANTING)
STORM: Is everybody okay?
(GROANS SOFTLY)
(GASPS)
No!
Behind you.
Ah!
(GRU NTING)
(SCREAMING)
COLOSSUS: Now!
(SCREAMS)
(SU NSPOT SCREAMING)
(GROANS)
HAN K: I'm probably not supposed
to ask this kind of thing...
but in the future,
do I make it?
No.
But we can change that.
Right?
(ROARING)
Do what you were
made for.
(GRU NTS)
Where are you?
Ah!
(GROANS)
(ROARS)
I got this! Go!
(LOGAN COUGHS)
(GROAN ING)
(GRU NTING)
Oh, dear God, no.
(SCREAMING)
So much for being
a survivor.
(GASPING)
(GLASS CRACKING)
(ALARM RINGING)
(DETECTOR BEEPING)
One of them is in here.
(MEN SHOUTING)
TRASK: No, no, no!
Don't kill it!
I need it alive.
(RUMBLING)
(GRU NTING)
What the hell
has happened?
(METAL CREAKING)
(ALL GROAN ING)
(IN HALING)
(GROANS)
You built these
weapons to destroy us.
Why?
Because you are
afraid of our gifts.
Because we are different.
Humanity has always feared
that which is different.
Well, I am here
to tell you...
to tell the world...
you are right
to fear us.
We are the future.
We are the ones
who will inherit this earth.
And anyone who
stands in our way...
will suffer the same fate
as these men...
you see before you.
Today was meant to be
a display of your power.
Instead I give
you a glimpse...
of the devastation my race
can unleash upon yours.
Let this be a warning
to the world.
And to my mutant brothers
and sisters out there...
I say this.
No more hiding.
No more suffering.
You have lived
in the shadows...
in shame and fear for
too long. Come out.
Join me.
Fight together in
a brotherhood of our kind.
A new tomorrow...
that starts today.
(GROANS)
MAGN ETO:
All those years wasted...
fighting each other,
Charles.
To have a precious
few of them back...
(RUMBLING)
(BANGING)
(GROANS)
MAN: Mr. President, sir.
Stand down.
I said, stand down!
You want to make
a statement?
Kill me. Fine.
But spare
everyone else.
(GRU NTING)
Very heroic,
Mr. President...
but you had no intention...
of sparing any of us.
The future of our
species begins now.
(GU NS COCKING)
(BEEPING)
(GASPING)
You used to be
a better shot.
Trust me,
I still am.
Get out of my head,
Charles!
Raven.
Please, do not make us
the enemy today.
Look around you.
We already are.
(BREATH ING H EAVILY)
CHARLES: Not all of us.
All you've done so far...
is save the lives
of these men.
You can show them
a better path.
Shut her down, Charles.
I've been trying to control
you ever since the day we met...
and look where
that's got us.
Everything that happens now...
is in your hands.
(BREATH ING DEEPLY)
I have faith in you,
Raven.
(SCREAMING)
(EXHALES)
(IN DISTINCT MU RMU RING)
RAVEN: He's all
yours, Charles.
(GRU NTS)
If you let them have me,
I'm as good as dead.
You know that.
I know.
Goodbye, old friend.
Goodbye, Erik.
(H ELICOPTER HOVERING)
(SIGHS)
HAN K: Are you sure you
should let them go?
CHARLES: Yes.
I have hope for them.
There's going to be a time,
Hank, when we are all together.
HAN K: What about Logan?
(SOFT '70s SONG PLAYING)
The first time
(GROANS)
Ever I saw your face
I thought the sun...
(BELL RINGING)
KITTY: Buckminster Fuller is a
great example of an architect...
whose ideas were very similar
to those of a utopian future.
Good morning, Logan.
Late start. (CH UCKLES)
(IN DISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Have a good lunch.
Good job.
STU DENT: Thank you.
STORM: Very good job.
LOGAN: Storm.
Jean.
Hey, Logan.
Are you okay?
You're here.
Where else would I be?
Whoa.
Easy, pal.
(CH UCKLES)
Well, some things
never change.
It's good to
see you, Scott.
Uh-huh.
See you
later, Jean.
Professor.
Logan, is everything
all right?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think it is.
You did it.
Did what?
Logan, don't you have
a class to teach?
A class to teach?
History.
History?
Actually, I could use
some help with that.
Help with what?
Pretty much
everything after 1973.
I think the history I
know is a little different.
Welcome back.
It's good to
see you, Charles.
It's good to see everyone.
Well...
I had a promise to keep.
You and I have a lot of
catching up to do.
Yeah.
What's the last thing
you remember?
Drowning.
CHARLES: The past.
A new...
and uncertain world.
CHARLES: A world of
endless possibilities.
And infinite outcomes.
You kidding me?
Oh, he's alive!
(COUGHS)
CHARLES: Countless
choices define our fate.
Each choice,
each moment...
a ripple in the river of time.
What do you want us to do
with him, Major Stryker?
CHARLES: Enough ripples...
and you change the tide.
I'll take him from here.
CHARLES: For the future
is never truly set.
(CROWD CHANTING
IN FOREIGN LANGUAGE)